Aku Alatao

Blockchain/Software Engineer

netragonlong@gmail.com +1 812 809 4741 Toronto, Ontario, Canada



SUMMARY

Aku is a highly-skilled, self-motivated and task-driven professional with 10 years of experiences in Desktop and Web software development and 4 years of experiences in blockchain development in the sphere of Ethereum, Solana, Cosmos, Polkadot, Aptos and Sui blockchains.

Aku was born in Ottawa and studied software technologies in HK, China and came to Toronto, Ontario, Canada. He maintains good relationships with team members and leads the team atmosphere in a global team of diverse cultures. (be flexible with work time zone) He is always sensitive to new technologies and is not afraid to learn new technology, ignoring all experiences for better solutions.

EDUCATION

The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

Hong Kong | April 2009 - March 2013 Faculty of Engineering

WORK HISTORY

Meeiro Finance | Rust/Move Engineer

Remote, Lisbon, PT | May 2020 - April 2023

- Won the Polkadot Asia and Latam Hackathon 2022, 2023 twice.
- Participated in developing shear blockchain a parathread in polkadot ecosystem
- Developed NFT pallets and custom token pallets using substrate frame.
- Wrote swap and staking smart contract using ink! wasm smart contract system.
- Migrated crypto yield-farming contract written with pure Rust into using Solana Anchor framework and extended to dual-yield and triple-yield farming strategy.
- Developed move smart contracts of IDO launchpad and coin staking and built a meeapt swap by using hippo aggregator swap in aptos ecosystem.
- Co-worked with frontend/backend engineers in the agile environment.
- Raised \$400,000 in first IDO, ensuring high security and excellent quality of the MVP
- Took part in Sui Move Challenges which was held during Sui Event in Vietnam.
- Raised \$200,000 in first IDO and \$100,000 in NFT sale after developing solana rust program for IDO launchpad and NFT staking platform.
- Accelerated the development schedule in order to fulfill the promised timeline for an IDO launchpad that was delayed by a previous developer who has fired after this work
- Research about building company's own chain using Cosmos SDK on cosmos ecosystem and using Polkadot PDK as a parachain.

Automated Systems Ltd | C++, C# Developer

Hong Kong | May 2014 - Feb 2020

20+ long term projects using C++, MFC, .Net / Forte 9, 10, 11, ScanScore, FortePlayer

- Built 30+ .Net Services and developed Winforms admin pages to manage 7M Amazon Products automatically for purchasing and sales and resulted in over \$155k in annual savings.
- Performed talented database administration for MySQL and PostgreSQL in Linux for 6 years, saved over \$100k of fee from AWS and ECS database hosting server with db optimization.
- Designed and developed the Chinese TianShen notation feature in 3+ Forte projects and grew revenue by 200% in first 11 months (representing 40% of company revenue).

- Improved efficiency on 5+ Forte sub projects speeding up project completion by 20%.
- ullet Increased client satisfaction from 84% to 97% in 2016 and awarded employee of the Month twice for performing great work.
- Troubleshot and fixed any threads and bugs, communicated with clients to provide knowledge, expertise, and support, ensuring that their requirements were fully met.
- Completed analysis, design and testing phases of software development life cycle.
- Researched and integrated design strategies, product specifications, development schedules and user expectations into product capabilities.

FunctionEight | Passionate C++/MFC Intern, Junior developer

Hong Kong | Feb 2013 - Apr 2014

- 5+ long term projects / Mail Magic Professional, Ez-Architect
- Built 5 customer-facing small windows applications which increased sales by 55%.
- Redesigned and developed Mail delivery and 2d-architecture design project and added new features to meet customer's needs.
- Troubleshot and resolved performance issues for mysql and sql server databases and software.
- Built 5 AJAX based ecommerce and financial web platform.
- Analysed, evaluated and developed new web and database applications.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: C, C++, Modern C++ (11+), Java, C#, SQL, Javascript, Python, Go,

Solidity, RUST, Move

Blockchains: Ethereum, BSC, Solana, Cosmos, Polkadot, Aptos, Sui

Libraries/Frameworks: Spring Boot, Hibernate, JSF, GWT, .Net Framework, .Net Core,

ASP.NET, ASP.NET Core, MVC API, Winforms, MFC, Entity Framework, Linq, Unit Testing Framework, T-SQL, Telerik, DevExpress, Qt, React.js, Tailwind CSS,Gin, ActixWeb, Axum, Tokio, Rocket, Yew SSIS, SSRS, IIS, CI/CD, Azure/Cloud, Scrum/Agile methodologies,

Power BI, WebAPI

Databases: MS SQL Server, Oracle, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Neo4J, Redis Other: Linux/Unix, Socket Programming, Backend Programming, Github,

Docker, Jira, Kubernetes, Terraform, AWS

CERTIFICATIONS

Tools / Platforms:

• SQL (Advanced) Certificate | HackerRank

https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/6901fbe57eb2

• Python Certificate | HackerRank

 $\underline{\textit{https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/adacb80a7ea6}}$

CONTACT ME

Telegram: https://t.me/netragonlong
Skype: live:.cid.1bf088802735c54a
Github: https://github.com/alleycat1

Linkedin: https://linkedin.com/in/aku-alatao-352175278